<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache Airflow – Home</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Apache Airflow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: ApacheCon Europe 2019 — Thoughts and Insights by Airflow Commiters</title>
      <link>/blog/apache-con-europe-2019-thoughts-and-insights-by-airflow-commiters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/apache-con-europe-2019-thoughts-and-insights-by-airflow-commiters/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Is it possible to create an organization that delivers tens of projects used by millions, nearly no one is paid for doing their job, and still, it has been fruitfully carrying on for more than 20 years? Apache Software Foundation proves it is possible. For the last two decades, ASF has been crafting a model called the Apache Way—a way of organizing and leading tech open source projects. Due to this approach, which is strongly based on the “community over code” motto, we can enjoy such awesome projects like Apache Spark, Flink, Beam, or Airflow (and many more).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this year’s ApacheCon, Polidea’s engineers talked with Committers of Apache projects, such as—Aizhamal Nurmamat kyzy, Felix Uellendall, and Fokko Driesprong—about insights to what makes the ASF such an amazing organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polidea.com/blog/apachecon-europe-2019-thoughts-and-insights-by-airflow-committers/?utm_source=ApacheAirflowBlog&amp;amp;utm_medium=Npaid&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Blog&amp;amp;utm_term=Article&amp;amp;utm_content=AAB_NOP_BLG_ART_APC_001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;insights on the Polidea blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: It&#39;s a &#34;Breeze&#34; to develop Apache Airflow</title>
      <link>/blog/its-a-breeze-to-develop-apache-airflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/its-a-breeze-to-develop-apache-airflow/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-story-behind-the-airflow-breeze-tool&#34;&gt;The story behind the Airflow Breeze tool&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, we started contributing to this fantastic open-source project [Apache Airflow] with a team of three which then grew to five. When we kicked it off a year ago, I realized pretty soon where the biggest bottlenecks and areas for improvement in terms of productivity were. Even with the help of our client, who provided us with a “homegrown” development environment it took us literally days to set it up and learn some basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is how the journey to increased productivity in Apache Airflow began. The result? The Airflow Breeze open-source tool. Jarek Potiuk, an Airflow Committer, will tell you all about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polidea.com/blog/its-a-breeze-to-develop-apache-airflow/?utm_source=ApacheAirflowBlog&amp;amp;utm_medium=Npaid&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Blog&amp;amp;utm_term=Article&amp;amp;utm_content=AAB_NOP_BLG_ART_AB_001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;how and why it’s a &amp;ldquo;Breeze&amp;rdquo; to Develop Apache Airflow on Polidea blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
