<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Use-Case on Apache Airflow</title>
    <link>/blocktype/use-case/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Use-Case on Apache Airflow</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="/blocktype/use-case/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Business Operations</title>
      <link>/use-cases/business_operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/use-cases/business_operations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-airflow-for-business-operations-pipelines&#34;&gt;Use Airflow for Business operations pipelines&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Airflow can be the starting point for your business idea! For many companies, Airflow delivers the data that powers their core business applications. Whether you need to aggregate user data to power personalized recommendations, display analytics in a user-facing dashboard, or prepare the input data for an LLM, Airflow is the perfect orchestrator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This video shows an example of using Airflow to run the pipelines that power a customer-facing analytics dashboard. You can find the code shown in this example &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/astronomer/business-operations-structure-example&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETL/ELT</title>
      <link>/use-cases/etl_analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/use-cases/etl_analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-airflow-for-etlelt-pipelines&#34;&gt;Use Airflow for ETL/ELT pipelines&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Extract-Transform-Load (ETL) and Extract-Load-Transform (ELT) data pipelines are the most common use case for Apache Airflow. 90% of respondents in the 2023 Apache Airflow survey are using Airflow for ETL/ELT to power analytics use cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The video below shows a simple ETL/ELT pipeline in Airflow that extracts climate data from a CSV file, as well as weather data from an API, runs transformations and then loads the results into a database to power a dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure Management</title>
      <link>/use-cases/infrastructure-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/use-cases/infrastructure-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-airflow-for-infrastructure-management&#34;&gt;Use Airflow for Infrastructure Management&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Airflow can interact with any API, which makes it a great tool to manage your infrastructure, such as Kubernetes or Spark clusters running in any cloud. As of Airflow 2.7, the setup/teardown feature is available, a special type of task with intelligent behavior to spin up and tear down infrastructure at the exact time you need it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure management is often needed within the context of other use cases, such as MLOps, or implementing data quality checks. This video shows an example of how it might be used for an MLOps pipeline. You can find the code shown in this example &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/astronomer/use-case-setup-teardown-data-quality&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLOps</title>
      <link>/use-cases/mlops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/use-cases/mlops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-airflow-for-machine-learning-operations-mlops&#34;&gt;Use Airflow for Machine Learning Operations (MLOps)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning Operations (MLOps) is a broad term encompassing everything needed to run machine learning models in production. MLOps is a rapidly evolving field with many different best practices and behavioral patterns, with Apache Airflow providing tool agnostic orchestration capabilities for all steps. An emerging subset of MLOps is Large Language Model Operations (LLMOps), which focuses on developing pipelines around applications of large language models like GPT-4 or Command.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
