<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache Airflow – Development</title>
    <link>/blog/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Apache Airflow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/blog/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Documenting using local development environment</title>
      <link>/blog/documenting-using-local-development-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/documenting-using-local-development-environments/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;documenting-local-development-environment-of-apache-airflow&#34;&gt;Documenting local development environment of Apache Airflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Sept to November, 2019 I have been participating in a wonderful initiative, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/season-of-docs&#34;&gt;Google Season of Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a pleasure to contribute to the Apache Airflow open source project as a technical writer.
My initial assignment was an extension to the GitHub-based Contribution guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the very first days I have been pretty closely involved into inter-project communications
via emails/slack and had regular 1:1s with my mentor, Jarek Potiuk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got infected with Jarek’s enthusiasm to ease the on-boarding experience for
Airflow contributors. I do share this strategy and did my best to improve the structure,
language and DX. As a result, Jarek and I extended the current contributor’s docs and
ended up with the Contributing guide navigating the users through the project
infrastructure and providing a workflow example based on a real-life use case;
the Testing guide with an overview of a complex testing infrastructure for Apache Airflow;
and two guides dedicated to the Breeze dev environment and local virtual environment
(my initial assignment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m deeply grateful to my mentor and Airflow developers for their feedback,
patience and help while I was breaking through new challenges
(I’ve never worked on an open source project before),
and for their support of all my ideas! I think a key success factor for any contributor
is a responsive, supportive and motivated team, and I was lucky to join such
a team for 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents I worked on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/airflow/blob/master/BREEZE.rst&#34;&gt;Breeze development environment documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/airflow/blob/master/LOCAL_VIRTUALENV.rst&#34;&gt;Local virtualenv environment documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/airflow/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.rst&#34;&gt;Contributing guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/airflow/blob/master/TESTING.rst&#34;&gt;Testing guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: It&#39;s a &#34;Breeze&#34; to develop Apache Airflow</title>
      <link>/blog/its-a-breeze-to-develop-apache-airflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/its-a-breeze-to-develop-apache-airflow/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;the-story-behind-the-airflow-breeze-tool&#34;&gt;The story behind the Airflow Breeze tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, we started contributing to this fantastic open-source project [Apache Airflow] with a team of three which then grew to five. When we kicked it off a year ago, I realized pretty soon where the biggest bottlenecks and areas for improvement in terms of productivity were. Even with the help of our client, who provided us with a “homegrown” development environment it took us literally days to set it up and learn some basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is how the journey to increased productivity in Apache Airflow began. The result? The Airflow Breeze open-source tool. Jarek Potiuk, an Airflow Committer, will tell you all about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn &lt;a href=&#34;https://higrys.medium.com/its-a-breeze-to-develop-apache-airflow-bf306d3e3505&#34;&gt;how and why it’s a &amp;ldquo;Breeze&amp;rdquo; to Develop Apache Airflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
